sports the thing you weren't quite good enough at for
your dad to love you. I absolutely love sports
. In fact, the only times I've cried as
a grown man have been while watching actors playing cultures
deliver inspirational speeches set to stirring music. This game
is not over. This battle is not over.
This is our time now. Second half is out
, weighed up all those inches. That's gonna make
the difference between winning Clear eyes. Full hearts way
are a lucky that Kyle Chandler is not a Scientologist
or I would be broke and married to Mimi Rogers
Right now. That's a fact. That's a true
fact. But look, tonight we're not going to
talk about the players on the field. We're gonna
talk about the fields themselves. Stadiums. America has
a lot off them, and they are increasingly fantastic
at the home of the Dallas Cowboys. Here's what
you also get really art by world renowned artists.
The party suite is all about watching the game or
concert in style. You can do bottle service,
you can set up. Come in before the game
, you know you get the snakeskin. You know
the ad, the gold Age Everybody knows where you're
sitting. There are 14 party cabanas and two pools
watched by lifeguards that looked out on the field.
Just look toward the end zone. Yep, those
swimming pools are inside the stadium. That's right.
You can now watch a game from a swimming pool
suspended above the field, where the real contest for
the fans is finding out whether or not HPV can
swim. My money's on HBV. That's a clutch
STD. That's clutch. Most new stadiums nowadays look
like they were designed by a coked up Willy Wonka
. And if you don't believe me, just look
at what the Miami Marlins have in Venue Ballpark.
That's a fish tank around the whole part. That
is awesome. Yes, the Marlins have actual aquariums
behind home plate, which is indeed awesome because you
get to watch baseball one of the same time watching
fish developed panic disorders. All those new finches are
clearly incredible. The problem is, they're also expensive
on. The vast majority of stadiums are built using
public money. One analysis found that between 4010 we
spent$12 billion building new facilities for professional teams,
which begs the question, Why sports teams are successful
businesses with wealthy owners, and yet they still get
our help. Two years ago, Detroit got approval
to spend more than$280 million in taxpayer money on
a new arena project for the Red Wings, just
six days after the city filed for bankruptcy. Even
though the Red Wings owner is Mike Village, the
founder off the Little Caesars pizza chain who's worth an
estimated 5.1 billion, that's a little hard to swallow
. I mean, sure, not as hard to
swallow as a Little Caesars crazy bread with an assortment
of Caesar tips, but still pretty hard. We
don't just help teams build stadiums. We let them
keep virtually all the revenue those stadiums then produce.
Just listen to the president off the Miami Marlins described
. They're not at all unusual deal. You get
the income from naming rights. Yes, you get
the income from concessions. Yes, you get the
luxury box income. Yes, you get the income
from non baseball events. That's the whole object of
this is to get more revenue. Wow, that's
that's pretty direct. You think I got into this
because our like sports one are you a child who
let a child host a television show. This is
all about the money, son. The money he
mentioned naming rights in there. And it is true
for most teams. If you sell the name of
your building, you get to keep the money.
Even when it's a stupid Is this the New Orleans
pelicans are going to be playing their home games at
the Smoothie King Center? Yeah, the Smoothie King
center on. You have to feel a bit for
the pelicans players. It can't be easy to protect
your home court when it's named after a slop of
yoga and kale ejaculated from a blender. But owners
monetizing every part of a stadium is so ingrained it's
even now a feature in the Madden NFL video game
. We're adding the ability to run your team as
an NFL. Being an owner isn't just about talking
, though. It's about taking action. Said prices
on concessions, merchandise and tickets upgrade your state,
improve everything from the parking lot to the locker room
. Incredible three Owner experience is apparently so realistic that
if you unlock a secret level, you can even
deal with the aftermath of making a racist comment.
That's that's incredible. Attention to detail for gamers Teams
Teams are so successful at pushing for upgraded stadiums that
since the early nineties we've had a replacement rate of
over 90%. We replaced stadiums even faster than we
replace Spider Men. Come on. What? Tobey
Maguire and Andrew Garfield were perfectly good state of the
art Spider Man. Almost every single team get some
kind of public money. Some, like the Yankees
, might build the stadium themselves, but on land
that they're given rent and property tax free, costing
New York City hundreds of millions in lost revenues.
But many others get their stadiums funded through tax exempt
municipal bonds, which, yes, sound like the
last words, an accountant says before his blind date
falls asleep at the dinner table. But they're actually
incredibly important. So so let me quickly try to
explain. Municipal bonds are away for the city to
take out a loan, which they then later repay
with interest, although usually through new or existing taxes
, they're supposed to be for things like roads or
schools, public goods that private industry would not pay
for. But they've been routinely miss used to finance
stadiums for decades, and often cities do it because
teams claim they can't afford to build stadiums themselves.
The Marlins got nearly$500 million toward their fish traumatizing
theme park by pleading poverty, although when Miami Dade
County tried to verify that something strange happened. Among
the questions they asked was, Can we see your
books? You said no, Right? Why didn't
you just open the books? Because it that easier
? Because in Major League baseball, history books are
just kept private. That's just how it is,
sure, but if the argument in Major League Baseball
history, that's just how it is always one,
we'd still have an all White League of Players gambling
on games, smoking cigarettes at the plate and dying
of syphilis. But that leaked documents later revealed that
despite denying they made a profit, the Marlins have
generated nearly 50 million over the previous two years.
And listen, pretending your poor is wrong, it
wasn't okay when Mary Kate Olsen went through her hobo
face. It's not OK now way haven't even mentioned
the ultimate bargaining chip that teams like to use,
threatening to leave right now. The Oakland Raiders,
the ST Louis Rams on the San Diego charges are
all threatened to move to Los Angeles unless they get
new stadiums. In fact, over the past two
decades, nearly half the NFL has been subject to
speculation about a move to L. A. It's
such a cliche that in the current Madden video game
, if you want a new stadium, a good
way to do that is to relocate the team on
the game. Even tells you the easiest choice financially
is. Guess where? Los Angeles on. If
you're a charges fan, that must be pretty infuriating
. Oh, come on, even might make believe
escapist entertainment is trying to move my King team to
L. A. In fact, charges fans are
currently so terrified their team might leave. Not only
are they campaigning to spend public money on a stadium
, they're doing it in one of the worst rap
songs of all time. Die Hard is almost went
on a rampage. I tell the lies. I
hope you understand why I got the best with the
best fans. Another hate them. They deserve a
brand new stadium, said Hagel. To find a
city, send eagle, the second largest city committee
Sindical making money put it back in our city.
Wait, wait, wait, wait. What?
What? Go back. Did he say second largest
city? That is a strange boast for a rap
song. You know, I got the second hardest
carcass on the second. Most paid. When I
go to the club, I get the second most
laid second mode. Second most. I'm not there
. I'm number to go. Number two teams are
shameless in manipulating cities fears. In 1997 the Minnesota
Twins even ran an ad showing a player visiting a
child in hospital with cancer on the tagline. If
the twins leave Minnesota, an eight year old from
Wilma undergoing chemotherapy will never get a visit from Marty
Cordova, which is less like the Make a Wish
Foundation on More like the maker threats. Founder teams
don't just use threats to get what they want.
They also promise that new stadiums can work economic magic
. The Milwaukee Bucks, who are also currently threatening
to leave if they don't get a new arena,
are running this out. Now. The ripple effect
starts here. This is Wisconsin's home from the court
to conserve France, forming a community with new development
, jobs and opportunity the ripple effect of a new
era begins today. It spreads across the with up
through bronze and across the great state of Wisconsin.
Cycle down Milwaukee Bucks for a start. I don't
think Wisconsin will be transformed by one new arena.
And also, if you really are looking to make
a tangible change, how about coming up with a
better slogan than fear? The deer dears aren't scary
. They're timid forest ponies with sticks on their heads
. I mean, oh, dear. Stadiums very
rarely revitalized their surrounding areas. All create large numbers
of permanent jobs. Just listen to one bar owner
near that new Marlins ballpark, he says, since
the stadium opened in 2012 not only of his profits
not risen on game days, his regular stay away
, afraid of the traffic Here is a business owner
. We don't see any changes that could even say
it's hurting us. Of course it is because no
one has ever said, Hey, let's go hang
out in the area around the stadium on. I'll
tell you why I got a new shirt and I
really want someone to vomit Miller Lite and not shows
all over. In fact, a major review of
almost 20 years of studies showed economists could find no
substantial evidence that stadiums had increased jobs, incomes or
tax revenues. Or to put that another way,
this one economist said to me, I love this
line. He said, You're rather than spend a
$1,000,000,000 on a stadium. You're actually better off flying
a plane over a city and dumping a$1,000,000,000 on
the populace and just letting them pick up the money
and spend it. That is a great idea for
the economy. But it is a fantastic idea for
a new reality show. Tune in this Sunday for
Ryan Seacrest's$1,000,000,000 dump only on NBC. And it
gets one step worse because when you use public money
to pay for expensive stadium, you might find yourself
unable to afford something you badly need. Hamilton County
in Ohio was estimated to spend 50 million last year
on debts and other costs for the Bangles on the
red stadiums, even though since building them, they've
had to sell a public hospital, cut 1700 jobs
and delay payments for schools because of budget gaps.
And it might not even end there because there's a
clause in the contract that states. If 14 other
NFL stadiums have something then taxpayers must by the Bengals
, that thing on here is how comprehensive that closes
. Taxpayers are also on the hook for all kinds
of future bells and whistles, some that haven't even
been invented yet. At some point, taxpayers have
also agreed to pay for a holograph replay machine someday
. It's true the Bengals have a deal whereby if
someone invents holographic instant replay in the future, the
county has to buy it for them. And that's
the kind of clause owners put into a deal in
order to take it out during negotiations. Which begs
the question. What else was in there way?
Want a hell apart? A submarine dock and a
monkey named Professor Banana starting out in the locker room
during halftime? Or we're moving the team to L
. I. But teams get these deals because they
know politicians will capitulate and give them whatever they want
. Remember Milwaukee? What just Monday, just this
Monday, their mayor argued for a new stadium deal
he admits is not perfect with this appeal to civic
pride. I was in China 10 years ago.
I was on the Great Wall of China, and
I had a Milwaukee T shirt on and on the
Great Wall of China. This guy Chinese guy came
up to me, said Milwaukee Bucks. That's important
to me. It's important to all of us.
Okay, okay. The only possible way that story
is true is if that Chinese man happened to be
former Milwaukee box player Easy and Alien Milwaukee Bucks.
Two seasons I averaged 8.6 points again box, and
you could almost sympathize, because when politicians do try
to stand up to teams, it can cost them
. Last month, the City Council of Glendale,
Arizona, voted to try and get out of an
awful deal with the Coyotes, whose hockey arena was
costing them more than$8 million per year. The
mayor held a public hearing, and it did not
go well. I support this team. It's you
that doesn't support any fort in this city, not
football and certainly not hockey. What you're doing is
childish. It's pathetic and it's just disrespectful. While
I can see her passion Israel, you don't get
to call someone childish when you are the one arguing
for spending millions of public dollars You don't have to
keep a joint slab of ice in Arizona. Just
days after that, protease fans raised money so that
she could taste the mayor for charity. Taser,
Taser, Taser. Go, go! Let me
out! Okay, okay, okay. First of
all, do you have to say Taser three times
before tasting someone? You're not tasting Beetlejuice on Second
, no one should want to state him so badly
. They're willing to electrocute an old man for it
on Look, I know sports can make people behave
irrationally. For instance, somewhere there is a man
with this actual tattoo of Tim Tebow as a center
. That makes no sense. But But we have
to come to our senses and stop signing these deals
. And if you think it will, John,
there's no way. It's just too hard. Let
me persuade you to fight back in The only way
that I know works on inspirational halftime speech set to
music theme. I need you to join me in
the have ourselves on emotional, inspiring talk. So
got around. I'm at home. You might want
to take a knee. I know things look bad
. These owners have been humiliating us for decades.
sure way could just give up. We could roll
over and let them do it to us for another
20 years. Way could do that right here.
Two nights. We could decide to fight back.
I'm not saying we shouldn't have giant aquariums in ballparks
full of terrified fish. Off course we should.
This is America. If we don't have them,
no one else will. But we should not be
using public money to pay for them. Yeah,
teams might threaten to leave. That might happen,
but I happen to believe that your cities are more
than just the teams who happen to play their ST
Louis stand up. Stand up. ST Louis on
. Look at me. You're more than just the
ramps. You're more than just a ramps. You're
a proud Midwestern metropolis, your home of the ST
Louis Arch. San Diego. You're the second largest
city in California. That's no nothing. That's no
nothing. That's a solid number two on you.
Cincinnati. You're the home of the Rock and Roll
Hall of Fame. That's Cleveland. What you that
you're the hometown of astronaut Jim Lovell, Andi Emmy
award winning actress Carol Kane. That's Cleveland as well
. Shit, I'm sorry. You might have toe
hang onto the Bengals, but for the rest of
you, for the rest of you, I want
you to look deep down inside your heart. I
want you to dig in there. I want you
to find something, and it's gonna seem time.
But it's the most powerful thing in the world.
And it's the word. No. No. So
when a billionaire asks you to buy him a hologram
machine that doesn't exist yet, what are you going
to say? That's right. On when when they
ask you for public money without opening their books.
What are you gonna say, Teoh? That's right
. When they ask you if they can keep all
the money for calling that arena Smoothie King Center,
what are you gonna say to them? Oh,
no, that's right. Because that's a stupid name
for anything, even a smoothie store. So listen
to me, because I want you to get out
on the next time a team comes around asking for
a new stadium, I want you to make them
pay. What you gonna go, Ugo?