your surface infiltration measurements and the implications for artificial recharge
. Here's a picture near the study area looking east
in the morning of Ah, this town 29 palms
is just east of Joshua Tree, um, and
discuss the purpose and scope of the study. The
main issue out there was a decrease in water levels
. Teoh increased pumping from increased population they had lost
. There was decreases of the water table by as
much as 35 feet 50 years. So the purpose
was to evaluate the potential for infiltration through surface deposits
at proposed recharge sites near Joshua Tree, California.
Scope of the study included Field data collection by using
a double ring in full trauma, ter um,
and collection of sir official material through Cory. Laboratory
Analysis of this official deposits calculation of sir official infiltration
rates from the infill trauma, her data and then
obtaining soil water parameters using computer program. Rosetta.
An interpretation of the data using the modeling program BS
two D, which is a unsaturated zone flow model
. So in outline of this talk, we're going
to discuss the study area, talk about how the
data that was collected parameter estimation and then modeling with
Viets to D and then discuss the conclusions. Um
, study area is about 120 miles east of Los
Angeles, California um, centered around the town of
Joshua Tree, California We've got 29 palms to the
east Yucca Valley to the west, and we've got
our major regional groundwater, so obeisance colored here we
have the Copper Mountain Groundwater sub basin. The warn
groundwater. So based in 29 palms groundwater, so
basin and then the groundwater. So based on that
, were mainly concerned with which is the Joshua Tree
groundwater. So basin recharge into the sub basin.
This either through flow across the yucca barrier here,
which is a series of faults and also recharged through
this inter minute quail wash, which flows due to
precipitation. Here in the little certain San Bernadino mountains
flow through the crowd wash, eventually closing the Yucca
Wash and it flows high enough can reach dry lake
bed of Coyote Lake. A significant feature in this
area is this black line here, which is the
Pinto Mountain fault, and it's a barrier to flow
between the Joshua Tree Groundwater sub basin and the Copper
Mountain groundwater. So busy this map Here is ah
, zoomed in detailed map of the study area.
We have the Pinter Mountain fault crossing from the south
west to the Northeast across map, and we have
two different proposed areas for recharge we have north of
the Penta Mountain Fault. This area here is the
ICA Wash on these two painful trauma test sites are
just on the fringe of the wash. Water recharged
north of the pent amount fall would be constrained,
contained by the fault and therefore would be more of
a water bank storage type situation. Water infiltrated south
of the fault, Um, would be more of
, ah, recharge of the aquifer system. So
data was collected had those info traumatize sites he saw
in the previous map. This here is a double
ring in full trauma. Ter. We seated this
into the ground as far as possible without disturbing too
much of the surface Shal material, um, and
then burn the edges to prevent leaking from outside edges
of the inflow trauma. Ter Each ring. These
are two separate rings here. Each ring is connected
to its own calibrated reservoir reservoirs calibrated a five gallon
intervals. Um, and testing is done by filling
the two rings to desired stage height so that they
were both equal and then regulating flow from the the
reservoirs into the rings to keep the stage height equal
throughout the testing. Therefore, the water removed from
the reservoir can be assumed to be the water infiltrated
through that ring. Uh, set up for this
ring is special in that we're trying to measure strictly
downward flow of water so the outside ring can flow
down there. But it can also flow laterally away
from the ring. But it also constrains the flow
of the entering so that flowed. Entering it should
be strictly downward movement. So the rate from the
entering would be your downward rave movement of water through
that that ring. And then this just shows this
set up and the study areas, you can get
a feel for the scenario. We're working it.
Here's the data that we God from doing the inflow
trauma tests. We have our three different scenarios of
settings In the study area. We have washed near
Washington on wash settings. You can see that are
wash provided the highest infiltration rates. We've got volume
her time. So we've got a greater on slope
here, which means a higher infiltration rate. You
can see that it it's less for the near wash
settings and further, more or less in the non
wash settings. One interesting thing to point out is
you can see with near wash and wash settings.
We have a very linen, your data you would
expect for infiltration that with the beginning, when infiltration
commences that you would have not only gravitational forces but
also matric potential forces. And as the water moved
further down in the subsurface, the gravitational forces would
predominate and the infiltration rate would decrease. You can
kind of see that here for our non wash setting
, you've got a slight exponential decrease on infiltration rate
with time and a believe that the reason you don't
see that for the near washing wash settings is the
men for cooperation rate is so high that you you
do not see that the exponential decrease and linearity is
reached very early on, uh, to prove her
toe kind of back. This point up, this
is in full trauma. Her data from a study
done an Antelope Valley where we had very low infiltration
rates some sites were actually almost zero. And you
can see here there is more of an exponential decrease
. And this is important because if you do expect
though infiltration rates, you want to make sure that
your study time is sufficiently long enough so that you
do reach linearity and you can't determine your infiltration rate
. So, as I said, surface scores were
collected at the infiltrate and feel trauma test sites.
This is, ah, the data from the laboratory
analysis of those surface scores. Uh, major point
here is the wash sites, which the site wanted
to have a greater percentage of sand. Um,
and not so much not is greater percentage of silt
. Now, keep in mind these are only the
first upper one foot of the study site. So
this doesn't necessarily describe complete subsurface. We also got
hydraulic conductivity is from this laboratory analysis. Um,
the hydraulic conductivity is do not necessarily match the infiltration
rates or the setting with which they were. These
sites are located. A Z can see. We've
got a higher hydraulic conductivity for one of these non
wash sites than we do. They wash sites and
you would expect the wash sites tohave higher hydraulic conductivity
due to the fact that they had higher infiltration rates
. Um, let's see. So our preliminary results
just from data collection before we got into the modeling
was that there was simple collection of surface infiltration rates
and core material. Um, the infiltration rates were
the Iast within the wash lower adjacent, awash in
still lower in the non washed, um, and
full trauma touch should be done. Um, should
be long enough. So that do reach linearity in
your data and soil texture data correlated with setting infiltration
. However, we did see the discrepancies in hydraulic
conductivity. So the next step in this process was
to two parameter estimation to obtain the van connection.
Constance, these describe the shape of the wedding front
as they wedding from moves through the unsaturated zone and
those air needed for input into the V s to
the model. So that was the main use of
this computer program, Rosetta. It also gave us
hydraulic conductivity values that we could compare with not only
the laboratory hydraulic conductivity ease, but also the values
we were planning on getting from modeling. The infiltration
did it. You can see that there is quite
it could be quite a big difference between the laboratory
hydraulic conductivity, values and the result of values.
Which is somewhat odd because the input for the Rosetta
program was simply the particle size data from the laboratory
analysis. You would expect that would be some some
comparison there. However, the techniques are different.
See, do you have different numbers? Um,
so I Yes, Yes, Um, I see
. And so our hydraulic conductivity values were six times
10 the negative five toe, almost two times 10
mega, five feet per second, which is in
the range of fine sands that silty sands which correctly
describes with study area. Um, so then we
used our hydraulic conductivity values and the bank A nation
parameters as input in the V s too deep,
and we use visas to D, which is a
unsaturated zone flow model to estimate hydraulic properties. Based
on our info trauma data, we also used it
to create infiltration rate curves using those laboratory and Rosetta
hydraulic on activities to match with the field data.
Um, we also evaluated effective layering on near surface
of infiltration rate measurements because subsurface is not always a
homogeneous bloc of sand that can be layering compaction.
Um, and then finally, we provided a rough
estimate of the wedding front. Arrival time for its
surface, a one acre service infiltration pond. Just
to give. Ah, a rough estimate of toe
win. Recharge would begin if you did build upon
. So here is ah, the user interface for
V S two D. And this is actually a
grated model of our in full trauma test. This
is the model demand blocked out here We have.
Ah, this is a radio model. So this
upper left corner would be considered that the very center
of your Narine we have our entering here bounded by
our info, trauma or wall on our outer in
, founded by the outside in from trauma or wall
. You see, we have pondered water here to
simulate pond water inside the infiltration rings. Um,
greeting below the directly below them for trauma is smaller
space, creating the kind of helps with the precision
of the the modeling. And here you can see
, we have some of the model options. Just
wanted to show all the different options you have.
Important thing is the computation of inner cell relative hydraulic
conductivity for non radium. Oddo's um, the arithmetic
mean could give you the the best results for radio
models where you have a smooth wedding front or smooth
wedding front. The geometric mean works well. However
, with infiltration into a very dry medium, you
have a very sharp wedding front. And so therefore
you need to use the upstream waiting option. Um
and then we chose the Vanga Nation model Teoh represent
the hydraulic kicked heuristic functions, and these were the
results of the V s to modeling RVs to D
. Modeling these top two Here are the wash sites
. These bottom Teoh are the near wash sites will
get to the non wash here in a second.
Um, you can see here we with the late
time data were matching well with our model field,
which is the black line and are actual field data
, which is the solid. This solid the line
. I'm not sure what that's not coming up.
Um, we have the The slopes match Well,
so we're getting the sand infiltration rate. However,
the cumulative infiltration is over estimated with our modeled results
and you can see the problem here is this early
time data. We're overestimating infiltration rates in the early
time. For all that, almost all of these
sites. Um And we're also, um the field
is here on this one here on this one there
on that one. And it would be, Yeah
, these air about the same. Um, another
thing to note here is that the Rosetta and laboratory
modelled curves compare well with one another, but underestimate
infiltration at these sites. Um, the conclusion I
got from this was that something in the near surfaces
, um, causing these discrepancies because you're Rosetta and
your laboratory values were derived from near surface material.
And you're also getting a difference in your infiltration rates
with near time data, which would be representative of
your near surface alluvial. You can see here with
the non wash sites. We don't have that problem
. The near surf are the near really time did
at near surface alluvial measurements. We have good matching
between modeled on field and lab here, um,
site for it's just kind of a mess. It
doesn't describe well, because we also have good matching
here between the field, the model in the laboratory
values as well. It's here. You can see
Rosetta's Still, for at least these three sites is
underestimating infiltration data, and Rosetta is the input.
The Rosetta is strictly particle size analysis, and it
doesn't accurately describe complex scenario. So because we saw
evidence for Sir official layer at the washing near wash
sites, we wanted to test the modeling program to
sensitivity the layering. Um, here we did two
scenarios, one with the three inch thick silt layer
and one with a three inch thick clay layer a
different depths of 25 and 10 feet, the low
land surface. The first thing to note is that
clay would have a lower hydro hydraulic conductivity, and
so you would therefore expect the que middle of infiltration
to be less for clay than you would sell.
You see here from these models that fairly equal.
So it's the difference between the permeability of your low
permeability layer and surrounding. Alu Veum doesn't control the
decrease in your infiltration rate caused by that layer as
Muchas, the proximity to the land surface layers close
of service, as you can see have a greater
effect on infiltration rate, then layers deeper in the
subsurface. This also shows that between two and five
feet. You start to lose your sensitivity to that
layering and anywhere between five and 10 feet. You
probably wouldn't predict the late detective layer four models around
, uh, at these links, models are on
it. Greater links might possibly be able to detect
those layers deeper, uh, deeper dubs. So
we know the model is sensitive to layering. We
have evidence for sir official low permeability layer. And
we wanted to test to see if that would have
any effect on our model results. So we tested
our wash near Washington on wash sites again. Here
, in the near wash, we have a 0.75
foot thick surface. Layers of the first of upper
0.75 feet is a low permeability layer. And you
can see that does help us match this in your
time data. Better than our scenario where there was
no layering. So there is evidence off, sir
, official layering here at this site there may be
further layering that would cause the better match here with
this later time data, you can see here the
near wash site, you have slightly better prediction or
estimation of infiltration for the near time data with this
layered model. Again, it's a 0.75 foot thick
surface layer. But once he gets to the late
time data, the there's really very little difference.
So there is evidence that there possibly could be a
surf sir official layer the near wash sites, but
it doesn't have as much of an impact on your
infiltration rate as it would in the wash sites,
and you can see with our non wash sites.
There's no difference at all between layered, homogeneous,
and therefore there's really no evidence for sir official low
permeability layer at the non wash sites. So the
results of the modeling was that at the non wash
sites, we had a good agreement between modeled and
laboratory hydraulic conductivity values, which means that the double
ring in full trauma ter is a useful in estimating
the rate of water movement through the subsurface. If
you're assuming homogeneous, um, hydraulic properties throughout the
subsurface, um, any layering for short tests such
as we did lesson five hours. I wouldn't tell
you any lettering below 2 to 5 feet. Therefore
, you may need to do longer test, Um
, and again the wash sites. Watch sites should
evidence for its official low permeability crossed Um, And
so the next step was to do upon simulations to
just give a rough estimate of recharge times if these
ponds were constructed. Um, we chose site to
site for his representative sites of the two recharge areas
we discussed earlier. Sightsee being north of the Pencil
Mountain Fault in Yuck. Awash in sight for being
south of Pinto Mountain Fault. A non watch setting
, um, the wedding front reached the water table
, which is 400 feet below land surface at about
336 hours for a site to which is roughly 14
days site for we had a lower infiltration rates.
As you'd expect, recharged took longer and was at
the war water table 1080 hours or 45 days.
Here's the recharge rates that we that were provided by
the model site to pond Recharge was 21 feet per
day, and Side five recharge was five feet per
day. Now these values air extremely low values for
recharge times because this model assumes only uniform hydraulic properties
throughout unsaturated zone and doesn't account for come compaction with
death and consolidation or changes in sub surface geology.
Just as a comparison upon and Victorville California recharge was
three years and infiltration rate was three feet when it
began and decreased 0.5 feet by the time um,
recharged began. Um, in the war in basin
area, we have a recharge pond where recharge time
took about three months so it can vary. But
again, these air extremely high values, and you
would expect lower values. Teoh changes in the sub
surface geology. So the overall conclusions was that the
study site in Joshua Tree is suitable for artificial recharge
, assuming the uniform hydraulic properties recharged by pond but
began at earliest, 14 45 days, Um