What? No. Yeah. Are you right?
One thing. No, no. Four. Allow
people what I could find a way friend part ready
for one. You know, woman Now. And
what over. But what you have? Yeah,
this one on What? No, I work that
way. Important. Yeah. Yeah, about Thank
you so much for the kind introduction, Erik.
So as he mentioned, this work has been done
in conjunction with two universities universities, Gajah Mada in
Indonesia and, of course, San Diego State University
. So since this is being recorded, I'd like
to say a few words to the Indonesian audience that
will be viewing this at some point climates young to
go and took part of when you actually gone.
Sudan Who messed it up when we start over Namazi
Younggu bigger and took Farahat Dhiren young men. Mexican
president has testes side Indonesia. That simply means thank
you for the Indonesian audience. So the thesis title
is using the analytic hierarchy process, or hp to
identify areas of potential slope instability incurring on your Indonesia
. I will be using the term landslide quite often
in this presentation. So I'd like to define what
that means. It is defined by Barnes, 1978
. As a downward outward movement of slow for materials
composed of land, rock or combination, it could
be further subdivided by geoscientists by material mechanism of movement
and rate of movement. But for this presentation,
I will be using the term landslide to refer to
any form of slope failure. Now, I also
like to introduce the concept of hazard and risk.
Hazard is the probability of occurrence of a certain geological
event, such as a landslide to occur in a
particular area. Risk is the potential of economic or
social loss that may occur from that hazard geological event
. So seeing this infographic hazards on the left assets
on the right where they overlap is risk. Now
, in this presentation, I'll be using the term
landslide hazard susceptibility. What I mean by that is
the probability of occurrence of any form of soap failure
in a particular area. So this study is based
in Indonesia, and I'd like to give some background
there. Indonesia is composed of more than 13,600 islands
. Five of them are considered the large principal islands
, but about 6000 of them are inhabited. The
population is about 250 million people. Compared to United
States, which is about 320 million people. Here
in Indonesia, the population is not evenly distributed.
In fact, on the island of Java, about
60% of the people live. It's about 150 million
people, and that's where this study is based to
give a little background on the regional geology. The
story here is heavily influenced by the conversion interaction of
three major tectonic plates, the Eurasian plate in the
north east, abducting Indian Australian plate in the south
and the east, the Pacific Plate in the east
, Indonesia as a nation has been consecutively ranked two
or three. That second or third as a nation
worldwide in terms of fatalities attributed to rain triggered landslides
. And I'm going to try to explain why that
is briefly so. This conversion margin here is called
the Soon Arc. It is one of the most
classic volcanic arc localities in the world, with a
well defined trench in a four arc basin defined by
the islands of Java and Sumatra. This conversion margin
has produced some very nasty earthquakes, including the 9.3
magnitude earthquake in 2000 for which created a tsunami that
garnered worldwide attention. In addition, it's also home
to some of the most explosive historic volcanic eruptions,
such as Oba Tambora Krakatoa, in addition to many
others. So if you were to get in an
airplane and look out in the horizon on the island
of Java, seen here is a picture of Mount
Merapi and Mountain More Babu. You would see volcano
after volcano back after volcano, all these volcanic edifices
off into the distance. And besides Theseventies that these
create which are quitter. Neri, relatively sensitive to
slope failure, Ashes plays, lahar, flow deposits
, things of that nature. They're also very steep
, and there are a lot of people living in
these areas directly on the flanks of these volcanoes,
as seen in this image. In addition, I
would like to remind you that we are on the
equator, where rainfall is above average compared to the
rest of the world. So all of these things
come together to lead to a situation where landslides are
very prevalent. So coming back into Java island where
the study is based, I'd like to draw attention
on this geological map by Smith at all 2008 to
this band of volcanic centres signified by these red triangles
on this map and surrounding each of them is a
lavender polygon which represents soon arc sediments. The sooner
our sentiments are composed of lahar flow deposits, ash
and clay layers, wretches and usually under lane by
massive and decide blocks with no significant betting and tertiary
limestone, my field area is located on the flanks
directly in one of these soon arc sentiment polygons right
here, seen by this red box, the moving
closer to my field area, which is called carne
on your regency in Central Java, Indonesia. A
Regency, by the way, is a second level
administrative division, which means it's equivalent to a county
in American terms. And this is a slope shaded
GM map of this, uh, study area,
and I hope you can see that it ranges from
70 meters at its lowest to 3300 meters at its
highest, and it includes the peak of Mount Lau
, which is the volcanic centre that is in this
area. No matter how is not an active volcano
. It has had a last eruption in 18 85
. But regardless, the geology of this region is
totally dominated by loud products. This is largest polygon
here on the geology map, which is the lahar
deposits from outlaw do and seen over here in light
blue is Critter Neri lower products, which is tends
to be exposed, and a site and bridges.
There are some other units here that are derived from
other volcanoes in neighbouring regions that have caused eruptions that
were explosive enough to deposit sentiments within this field area
. And there are also some small outcrops, relatively
small of tertiary and a site and limestone. Now
, before I talk too much about my master's thesis
, I want to introduce the problem here by talking
about my bachelors thesis. I went to Indonesia for
the first time in 2011 and did a program that
was a community empowerment program that had the goal of
developing and applying a method to teach. Indonesian nationals
had attacked hazard and risk from landslides, and as
a result of that, I also produced what I
called a landslide hazard susceptibility map where the green polygons
are meant to signify low hazard susceptibility and the red
ones are meant to signify high hazard susceptibility. But
I'd like to point out here that there's a lot
of blank spaces on this map, and that's because
the primary method I used to create this was visual
observation. I was out there looking for signs of
cracking signs of past landslide events, things of that
nature or active landslides using the hypothesis that areas where
there has been passed land sliders, active landslide,
there will be landslides in the future. But I
wasn't able to go to all these places because being
foreign and also there's a lot of steep topography and
a lot of dense vegetation and not a lot of
roads in the traditional sense that we know them.
Um, so this is was this was the result
of of that work. Now, the people that
I was doing this community empowerment project with, we're
doing this for class. They're doing this for the
requirements for bachelors graduation at the university s Gaja monitor
, and they went forward and they extrapolated out into
the entire region of plus or a Joe, which
is about 11 square kilometres. And if you notice
here, there are some V shaped topography lines that
indicate either ridges and valleys that are kind of blanket
it as green. I don't know the methods that
they used to extrapolated here cause it wasn't published.
It was turned in for an assignment at a university
. But I have a sneaking suspicion that it wasn't
very statistical. And the only reason I'm showing you
this map is to point out that we could probably
do a more justified job at making a landslide hazard
map. And that's the objective of this thesis.
To make a landslide hazard separately, Map for cargo
on your Central Java that uses and tests HP or
analytic hierarchy process as a slope. Instability predictor references
. Existing landslides assigns weights to slope instability or physical
conditions that lead to slope instability and extrapolates those weights
to outside areas. So this is what the animal
Karki process looks like an equation form. The goal
of it is to obtain an L S I value
, which indicates how much hazard there is. What's
the probability of a landslide to occur in that area
? It's a numeric value that is found by the
some of factor weights, times class weights, and
it will be easier to show this visually. So
let's say I have a set of physical conditions.
These are my factors. These are categories of physical
conditions such a slope. Steepness, geology, land
use, river proximity. This is just an example
. This whole thing is a demonstration to show you
how this is done. All of them are assigned
factor weights now on each factor. There are also
a set of classes. So in this case I
have three classes of slope steepness, which are ranging
There been numbers to indicate what is the slope steepness
? In what group does it fall in? So
let's say I have a slope steepness of 55 degrees
in a particular area. That means the class wait
in that area would be 550.7. I would multiply
that by one to have an overall contributing value to
the Ellis I of 0.7. Now, how then
do I get these factor in class weights? This
is done through the analytic hierarchy process via pair wise
comparison. So, for example, I'm going to
present three factors. Let's call them A B and
C. So let's say I know through theory or
observation, that B is twice as important to landslide
generation or a influencing slope. Instability as a following
A is twice as influential to soap instability at sea
and finally be is three times as influential to slope
instability as C. I then have these numbers,
which I can arrange in a matrix form and there
in verses here and I can solve for the principal
Eigen Vector, which gives me a consistency ratio.
The consistency ratio in this case is 30.79 tells me
how consistent my comparison values are. If I was
, for example to say that C is much more
important, then be in this case, then my
consistency value would shoot up because I've already established a
relationship between A. B and C, and it
wouldn't logically follow. But in this case, like
consistency, value is sufficiently low. Satti, 1980
who designed this is a decision making model so that
10% or less with sufficient so in this case were
much lower than that so we can move on now
. I set up my matrix again and I take
the sum of every column here, and then I
divide each cell individually by that some to create a
table of decimals, which is then produces a row
that could be averaged in my final average for this
outcome is my factor. Wait. So in this
case, based on my comparison assumptions for A B
and C, I produced a outcome that said Be
is my most influential to landslide generation, followed by
a followed by sea. So how do I apply
this to map generation? Well, this could be
done using raptors raster images and raster czar matrix arrangements
of numbers that can be used to depict map or
a raise of information. This is commonly how Slope
D. M's slope shaded D. M's are presented
, where you have a pixel that has a certain
resolution and a number is attached to it, and
then you have it displayed over in array. Now
, my goal in this study is to providing ls
I value for every pixel. So every pixel in
map format is going to have a certain slope steepness
value a certain geology, a certain land use certain
river proximity value. And if I have my factor
and class waits for all of these physical conditions,
and I can assign an l S I value across
the whole thing with the goal of detecting where is
the best fit area for landslide initiation or the highest
configuration of slope instability factors? This has been applied
in other field areas in terms of landslide hazard in
Iran, China, Nepal and Turkey, for example
. And they all found it somehow relevant to landslide
hazard analysis. They all had different hypotheses in different
objectives, but they all found it somewhat applicable to
this study. And the reason I'm putting the slide
here is just to demonstrate that I'm not the 1st
1 to have tried this. Now we'll talk about
my field area specifically. One point I'd like to
mention straight away is that I received a very important
bit of information from Luke Weidman and his bachelor's thesis
Weidmann 2014 because he did a community service apartment program
just like I did, but in a different area
in a different year, within the same blanket scarring
on your regency. And during his study, he
produced a inventory of evidence for slope instability as seen
here for an area called Step on John, which
is about six square kilometers now. Also for step
on, John, I have river network information,
land use, inroads, geology and topography data and
therefore have slope steepness. So these are the factors
I used in my HP model dark boxes. Here
are my factors and the lighter red boxes are the
classes within each factor. So how do I compare
these on a pair wise basis in order to get
my factor in class weights? Well, three of
these factors air numerical in nature, so that presents
a unique opportunity for me to do trend analysis between
my slope instability, evidence in step on junk and
these numerical values. For example, using distance to
roads here, I overlay distance to road polygons,
which are made with 40 meter increments made arbitrarily.
But now I can check to see if it actually
is related to anything on the ground. My goal
here is to figure out how much slope instability evidence
falls within each of these polygon. So if there
is to be a relationship between roads, distance two
roads that I'm assuming which is distance Saros road cuts
causes mawr exacerbation of slope instability and therefore landslides,
and there should be mawr evidence for landslides close with
roads and less and less as we get away from
it and that's exactly what we see for the most
part. So it looks like there is a negative
correlation between increasing percent area affected and distance from roads
, with the exception of 202 140 meters, which
of course, is explained by the fact that distance
the road is not the only reason are landslides in
this field area. So I also did this with
my other numerical values, including slope, steepness and
distance from rivers. And it turned out that slope
steepness appears to be the most related correlative to landslide
evidence and distance rivers that appears to be quite randomly
distributed. It happens to be the least related using
this method to my landslide inventory or evidence for slope
instability from Weidmann 2014 and that means that doesn't mean
that we can't use it. But the assumption here
is that it should be compared lower in terms of
the comparison data. So how then do I include
non numerical factors such as mythology and land use?
Well, I had to rely on some subjective assumptions
uh, the elements considered where data type, What
is the data actually showing me in the case of
geology. I have a map but doesn't have anything
about betting. Doesn't have anything about the soil thickness
. Is a parent geology or is it surface geology
? Well, in this case, it didn't have
any information about betting. Didn't have anything about the
type of soil above it or the thickness of soil
. So therefore, I weighed surface manifestations such as
slope steepness and land use higher than geology. In
this case, I also consider data quality. What
was the resolution in the date that the data was
taken and some references that have used HP and fast
. So based on this pair wise comparison, my
weight values ended up being slope steepness is the highest
contributor to slope instability, followed by land use,
and then finally, distance to river at the end
. So how then do I move on and get
my class weights? Well, this is done in
a similar way. I over laid each of my
factors individually with the evidence for landslide or slope instability
, and what I was trying to do here is
try to figure out how much evidence for slope instability
falls within each class. With the hypothesis again that
areas that show past land sliding or current land sliding
will show land sliding in the future. So in
this case, the case of land use, I
found that the most evidence for slope instability is within
the settlement presidential areas, followed by the lower basis
plant, paddy fields and the agriculture. Now the
way I did. My pair wise comparison of these
classes is proportional to the size of these bars.
So in this case it looks like settlement Residential is
a little bit under twice is biggest lower basis plant
and just a bit bigger than Patty Field. So
when I made my comparison values, I ended up
comparing them in such a way that made class weights
that are proportional to go to that graph proportional to
the evidence for slope instability found within them. I
did this for all of my classes and all of
my factors to create unique values for each glass and
each factor, and therefore be able to apply the
LS I values to a map within CEPA and Young
, which looks like this. So there's some patches
of red, but overall there's a lot of green
zone one into areas. There's some yellow associated with
the red. So I check if this makes any
sense. Well, the easiest way to do it
would be to look at the evidence for slope instability
and put it back on my final map because this
was used to create this map. So this is
circular here. What I should see is I should
see a very strong, positive correlation between donation class
and increasing evidence for soap instability. And that's exactly
what I see. So it turns out that there's
a strong linear relationship in this case between miso nation
increasing with the most evidence for soap instability falling into
red and yellow classes. So now that I have
this information, what I have done is I've described
the inventory that I input into the map. Haven't
I have theorized what the ground truth is? But
what I've exactly done is produced a set of values
of factoring class weights that exactly describes the landslide inventory
within step on junk. So what would happen then
, if I applied? Those factor in class waits
to an area where I don't have any landslide inventory
control. This is telling Manu it's a sub district
. It's just an administrative level up higher than seven
. John, Where is which sits right here.
It does include the peak of Mount Lahu there.
So when I apply those factoring class waits, I
make a map. It looks like this. Now
the red patch here, just visually is red patch
here, near to the peak of Mount Lahu,
which indicates steep slopes. But over here we have
an intermediate area that's still steep, but these are
dense forests were not. A lot of people are
living and then we have these large red areas that
are the combination of people living in settlements on steep
slopes, possibly near rivers, possibly near roads and
possibly on lahar type geology. Then also, what
would happen if I extrapolated throughout the entire car in
on your regency? So this is this is tell
him and you in relation to car ng on yee
are just as an indicator here. And when I
apply, my factoring class waits to Carling on your
It produces a map that looks like this now just
visually inspecting this, it appears to me that there
is a clustering of red values red area in the
northeastern portion of car nine yard. We'll come back
to that. But first I'd like to discuss how
do I test these maps? How do I check
to see if they actually work in any way?
Well, the first way I'd like to do that
is to introduce a piece of information set of data
that hasn't yet been mentioned. And that is the
landslide incident. Reports from Baby Day card Manyara,
the disaster management office that responds to and reports disasters
within this area. So that's me. And as
the leader of Big Redecard on yard, my advisers
from Indonesia and some Indonesian students and Kenneth graduated last
year, who visited Indonesia to do his own bachelors
thesis during this period of time and then some workers
for baby, they card on your now. They
have been taking incident reports on landslide since 2008.
They just began in 2008 and they very graciously gave
me all the incident data that they had for landslides
between 2010 and 2012. Now, this information was
in document based format. It was not digital in
any database. Um, and it didn't have any
GPS coordinates, so I couldn't use it as a
geo referenced landslide inventory, which would have been very
helpful in producing my comparison values. For the HP
analysis, however, it did have a lot of
very good information regarding incidents. Uh, statistics of
money in amount of victims, things of that nature
. There's about 268 reports, and it also they
each had address information on them. So down to
the lowest administrative boundary that I have in my yeah
yes platform, which is the village the day So
level Aiken been these incident reports to see where they
are coming from just in general. So one of
the early goals of this thesis was to create an
incident report input form that would automatically make an Excel
database of these incidents. So what I did is
I scripted this using visual Basic and Microsoft Excel with
the help of Dr Gallagher. These programming class and
I presented it to the Baby Day office in late
2013. It's an Indonesian language. It uses all
the information that they input on their incident reports already
, Um, but it's only having to do with
landslides, and I I never received any information further
about this. I put Bill no down here in
case there's any errors to please contact us, and
we can help you through it, etcetera. But
I never heard anything back, and I can only
assume that it probably wasn't used. Even though I
spent a couple hours out there with a translator training
someone had used it. They're very enthusiastic about it
. They like the idea, but my thought is
it's probably not robust enough. There's a number of
reasons why this could have gone wrong. It doesn't
have the narrative that they put in the incident reports
themselves, which is very cultural and characteristic. It
was meant to be done alongside the instant reports,
which is adding work to them. And if they
don't see the benefit, then there might be no
incentive to do so. And they might have need
something might have needed something that dealt with more than
just landslides, which is all this is is referring
to regardless, I was still able to use this
incident report form to make my own database in order
to check to see if my car go on your
map correlated with the distribution of incident reports so I
will discuss the results. This is the map that
was produced by the distribution of incident reports within car
gone yard. And the graduated color here, ranging
from light orange to dark orange, indicates how many
instant reports refer to that village in terms of victims
or location of landslide. And what it appears to
me here is that there's a clustering of incident report
High incident report villages in the northeast corner of Garden
Yard. If I put a broad circle around that
and I bring back my HP map just to visually
see how it correlates, it appears to me that
they fall. It falls roughly in the same cluster
of red that I identified in the HP prediction.
So viewing that statistically if I plot the top 10
red zones by percent area in yellow on this map
in the top 10 landslide incident report generators the top
10 villages that I referred to within incident reports in
appeal and the villages that have overlapping data in green
. What you see is there are four villages out
of the top 10 producers of landslide incident reports that
were identified by the HP prediction and in addition,
There are some other villages here that are identified by
the HP prediction that are adjacent to five of the
other incident report generators in this area. So this
demonstrates to me that there is indeed a clustering of
both data within the same area. So this is
somewhat of a great success, for it supports the
model of HB as a predictor of regional slope instability
. But we'll discuss that more in the discussion section
. So I also have a map for town man
you, which is a little bit smaller scale.
And I was actually able to take this map directly
to the field earlier this year. So I had
the wonderful privilege to go back to Indonesia in March
of this year. About a month and 1/2 ago
, I brought this map with me and I came
to the field with the goal of locating serious landslides
to see how they matched up with my predictions.
And I found four sites of serious land sliding,
and I'll just just each one of them individually.
So first is site one. This is me for
scale. This is an extremely large landslide about 95
meters in with and it occurred directly adjacent to this
major road in an area where it's largely homogeneous soil
with pebbles of tough and and a site boulders.
So it's happening on a steep slope that was modified
by farming activity. It occurred in late 2014 according
to local knowledge, and it also occurred alongside other
landslides that were secondary. That didn't occur at the
exact same time, but they occurred in Uh uh
in the same month, is what I was told
by locals has this primary landslide, So there's about
two very large ones here. All this also discussed
site to, which is about 500 meters up the
road, which is slightly smaller. It's about 32
meters in size and this is the thing. Very
similar physical condition right next to the road in thick
, homogeneous soil with steep slopes and farming conditions.
Now this clustering of landslides in certain physical conditions because
although this is 500 meters away, it's almost the
same story. A site one indicates to me that
there is a value in looking for the configuration of
physical conditions, to look for soap instability just as
an aside there. But how did they plot with
my HP prediction? And what I found is that
they seem to plot in an area that is marked
as green as one and two. So before I
move on to far here, I want to mention
that there will be landslides in areas that are marked
as green. There is a certain percentage that must
happen in them in order for them to fit this
model. But given that these physical conditions air causing
landslides in more than one area, you would hope
that the HP method would detect these in yellow or
red area. Now, the next important thing I
want to point out is this purple line here which
indicates the major road, which is on the order
of 506 100 meters away from these sites. But
if you look at these pictures, it appears the
major road is directly next to these landslides. So
I thought maybe my GPS coordinates are wrong. I
went to a satellite image, imploded these sites there
, and it seems, in fact, that they
are plotting next to a linear feature seen here as
a tan line with dark red dashes. This is
a road that's under construction. So this road was
under construction in 2013 and my data was from 2012
so it didn't include this road, this major road
. If you see this right angle here that's going
off to the east with it's indicative bump, that's
the right angle right there. The indicative bump that
I'm referring to in my model I have not included
the updated road in my HP model, and it's
my belief that if I did, it would have
had the ability to bring it up in rank from
either yellow to red because it would have had the
road distance checked. It would have had a disturbance
of the soil. And there's also land use that
has been created as a result of this road,
so moving on insight. Three. This is a
very large landslide, the worst in recorded memory in
these Indonesian in this Indonesian area. This landslide occurred
during morning and it killed 65 people in 2007 so
it happened on a very steep slope with modification by
farming, and it was about 100 meters and with
so how did this very seriously landslide plot on my
HP mapple. It seems to have been targeted right
into an area of yellow and red. Now it's
a big white circle because it's too large landslide and
there's little bit error associated with it. However,
when you consider it against the background noise of green
areas, I see this is a very strong supporter
of the H B as a predictive predictor of this
type of landslide, so moving on to site for
which is a completely different kind of landslide. Now
, this is a creeping landslide that occurred over a
long period of time and it's still ongoing and it's
very special because I was able to visit it over
this period of time while I was living in Indonesia
. So this is September 2012. This with me
and Kenneth again and my advisers and a driver looking
at cracking in the ground, standing on pavements near
this home and their vegetation down here. But we
can easily walk past this site here in September 2012
moving forward in January 2013 about four months later,
The area where we're standing actually isn't there anymore.
This is receded back completely. The house that used
to be there has been evacuated and scrapped and now
this scarf here is about probably 3 to 4 meters
in height. You could still walk across this area
now moving forward to August of 2013. The area
that I just pointed out that it could be walk
across is completely gone. It's completely eh vegetated.
And they've implanted this poll here to indicate further land
movement. Now. I also went back of this
in this year in March and this is what I
saw. This poll has been significantly strained and stressed
, so this landslide is still ongoing today. Although
it's a different kind of landslide completely. How does
it plot within my HP map prediction and it appears
the flooded area that's marked very largely relative to the
other ones as red. I'd also like to point
out here while we're on the slide to the southeast
. There's this large red area into the west.
There's another large area in which no similar slope instability
was seen. But I also want to point out
, just like when, just like were ableto have
landslides in green areas. We're also able to observe
red areas that don't have landslide processes and I also
want to remind you that what this model has actually
done exactly is look for areas that are similar to
the landslide conditions to the physical conditions that were produced
. Landslides within seven junk the inventory that was input
into the model. So this is read exactly because
it is very similar to the conditions which caused landslides
in adjacent area. So just because it doesn't have
land sliding now doesn't mean that it can't in the
future, but should be noted that there is quite
a liberal painting of red along this area, so
results overview regionally. It successfully identified HP as a
model successfully identified areas known to be high producers of
landslide incident reports. It's like one into it failed
to detect these very serious large landslides attributed to having
outdated data. Site three successfully placed serious landslide against
a background of green area and site for successfully placed
the creeping event in a larger area. Overall,
there was many red areas without soap, instability,
evidence scene. So now let's have some discussion about
this. First, I'd like to point out some
potential sources of air in this method. First of
all the inventory that was very kindly given to me
by Luke Weidmann 2014 was I never meant to be
extrapolated, enforced on to the entire region. I
was actually fortunate enough to participate in some in a
very brief period of actually taking this inventory. And
, um, it includes not only landslides but rockfalls
and creeping and evidence for cracking things that actually haven't
fallen yet. This may account for some of that
liberal presence of red area that we saw on the
map. In addition, the data are clustered near
roads because just like in my thesis, where I
wasn't able to see the entire area, we used
the roads. We used motorbikes. We walked around
in order to make this information. I'm sure this
is the similar case for this thesis. So therefore
landslides that are near road are preferentially reported. In
addition, in my factor choice, I have slow
class river channel proximity and road proximity, all with
the intention of looking for slope channels. So slope
steepness And the reason I did this is because my
slow class map is made from a topography, met
from contour lines and therefore I couldn't haven't be too
high resolution because it started to create artifacts in the
data. So the resolution of that slope map is
pixel sizes of 50 meters by 50 meters, so
anything below 50 meters any change in slope below 50
meters would not be detected. Be sort of averaged
out according to the topography map. So I needed
some information from the river channels which arm or localized
in the road cuts, which are known to be
a large producer of landslides in this area. So
that being said, I have some well, first
, let's have some conclusions. I found HP to
be extremely useful, particularly for a preliminary landslide study
in an area where you have never been or you're
unable to go, particularly with areas in Southeast Asia
where there are wide areas of land that have never
been analyzed by geologists. This is a very low
cost, an attractive method for approaching those areas,
especially initially. Now I say low cost. Having
said that, the data I used was practically free
. I used information that was primary. I used
remote sensing information. I used information from past DC's
. However, uh, we found that there was
an issue with some of my data being updated.
I mean said you could potentially spend a lot of
money and put new data in here, and I
have some suggestions for a future study. And a
lot of these suggestions are actually for myself because I'm
currently working on a proposal or grant in order to
outline how this could be done another time in either
another area of the same area to achieve a much
more valuable effect. And what I recommend doing is
including high resolution D. M within it. So
maybe lied are imagery. This would eliminate the need
tohave roads in river channels as a factor completely,
so long as your slope class map is high enough
resolution to detect those features. You could, however
, have roads as vibration sources in river as something
to do with the hydrology situation, but they would
be set up differently in that event. Also,
I recommend a have a fit for purpose landslide inventory
. What I mean by that is one that is
made for HP, either one that is produced from
a database that is from the Disaster Management Office Baby
Day. Calling on you are that includes landslides from
all over scarring on your or one that is made
with a certain goal in mind, such as if
I'm only looking for classic translational rotational landslides in thick
soils above the thes the parent geology maybe above 30
meters squared affected area that I would only map those
those in my inventory and HP would give me exactly
the conditions that are conducive only to those landslides.
Also, I recommend putting some unique factors. Soil
thickness, rainfall distribution, Ashley ash, clay layer
coverage, vegetation analysis, etcetera. I believe that
this system allows for more complexity, and it benefits
from that. So because you can compare things on
a pair wise basis, more complexity is better.
So long a special care sticking to avoid redundancy in
the factors you don't want to types of factors that
are getting at the same physical condition, and also
it is very low cost to run HP once the
data is obtained so you can do it a number
of times once you have made a map, if
you have direct access to the field area, you
can take it and go to the field. And
if you find a landslide or something, that contradicts
your map. You can rearrange your weights and classes
and accommodate that in the landslide inventory without taking new
data. So once you've made the investment, you
can run it as many times as you want.
You can update it, and it could be relevant
to the time that it's created. So with that
, I will conclude. But I would like to
give some very well deserved acknowledgements, including to Dr
Dweik, read a carnal wadi or Emerita, as
we have come to call her for inviting me to
Indonesia in the first place. In 2011 she very
kindly allowed me to sit in on a meeting and
in that meeting without even knowing me, invited me
to go to a university to go to her country
. And that led to a 1.5 cumulative years of
living there in doing a dual degrees. And I
have a lot to thank her for for that.
In that regard, Dr Hua Hui Lopo for helping
me with the field excursion. He provided the translators
, the cars, the field equipment and he was
always saying yes to. Whenever I wanted to go
to the field, even when I came and Short
noticed early this year for 10 days, he said
, OK, let's go right now and then Dr
Eric Frost, of course, for a lot of
the same reasons as a burrito for putting the trust
in me to go and do this study abroad experience
without knowing me at all. Really? In 2011
when I first met him, I said, I
want to do something That was for the community.
Wanted to use geology to help people and he said
, Well, I have someone I'd like you to
meet And then it became This experience has completely changed
my education and really has completely changed my life because
of the some of the personal relationships that I have
maintained as a result of this experience. So I
could talk about that forever. But I'd like to
keep it brief. So also, faculty and students
of STS you geological science, especially Luke for allowing
me to use his landslide inventory in this study and
the faculty students of you, GM, geological Engineering
and to them, I'd like to say three Mukasey
Pseudomonas ton president Dusty SIA Oh, some will give
Berman fat Maggie Kita Samuel. Which means thank you
for watching this presentation. I hope that you all
found it valuable. I will be happy to open
the fourth question. Yes, when?